<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Copy &amp; Paste is for Word</title>
    
    
    <description>This website is a virtual proof that I'm awesome</description>
    
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Implementing Progressive Web Apps with React</title>
        <description>
          
          Here is my third book. Did you know that with PWAs you can create Web Apps that deliver a user experience similar to native apps? Did you know that with the React tooling most of the work to create them is almost done? I will explain how to create PWAs...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2022-06-20-pwa-react/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2022-06-20-pwa-react/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding React</title>
        <description>
          
          Here is my second book. Learn how to code applications in React by following a solid path that starts by studying essential JavaScript constructions to then go into React core concepts to finally write an application. Understand how to split an application into components (class or function-based ones), how to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 19:12:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2021-12-25-understanding-react/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2021-12-25-understanding-react/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coding an Architecture Style</title>
        <description>
          
          I have just released my first book about hands-on Software Architecture. If you want to know how to design and code an application with Modular Architecture, or with Layered Architecture or with Hexagonal Architecture (Clean Architecture), or with Microservice Architecture this book is for you. If you are a developer...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 20:12:13 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2020-06-12-coding-architecture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020-06-12-coding-architecture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Object Oriented Frameworks: Concepts, White Box and Black Box Examples</title>
        <description>
          
          When teaching Object Oriented Frameworks (usually in Advanced Object Oriented Programming courses) there is a challenge for students to understand their nature, differences with libraries and the difference between white box frameworks vs black box frameworks. In this post I will start talking very briefly about general concepts of frameworks....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2016-06-11-frameworks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016-06-11-frameworks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Architecture vs Software Design</title>
        <description>
          
          I cannot find in the literature a precise distinction between Software Architecture and Software Design. Of course, I did not read all the books about software Architecture available in the market, but I read two great books, which I recommend (mentioned on footnotes below), but neither of them, IMHO, are...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 20:12:13 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2011-07-13-arch-vs-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2011-07-13-arch-vs-design/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Note on the Definition of Legacy Code</title>
        <description>
          
          Many developers think that Legacy Code is an old code base that they inherit. A working application that other developer or other team wrote and you inherit it to maintain or enhance or to migrate to a newer platform. This is not entirely true, according to the definition of Michael...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 20:12:13 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2011-06-20-legacy-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2011-06-20-legacy-code/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the role of a Software Architect ?</title>
        <description>
          
          If you are an Architect you may have discovered that you are not going to be asked to spend all your time on improving the design of an existing software product, nor to write code for an specific project. As soon as you become an Architect, your meeting’s calendar will...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 20:12:13 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2011-05-22-architect-role/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2011-05-22-architect-role/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
